<resources>
    <string name="app_name">NationalParks</string>
    <string name="nav_passport">Passport</string>
    <string name="nav_explore">Explore</string>
    <string name="nav_map">Map</string>
    <string name="parks_error">Failed to load park list</string>
    <string name="search_placeholder">Search parks, states, or trails</string>
    <string name="explore_heading">Explore Parks</string>
    <string name="elevation">Elevation</string>
    <string name="visitors">Visitors</string>
    <string name="area">Area</string>
    <string name="elevationMeters">%1$s m</string>
    <string name="elevationFeet">%1$s ft</string>
    <string name="areaMeters">%1$s km²</string>
    <string name="areaMiles">%1$s mi²</string>
    <string name="aboutPark">About the Park</string>
    <string name="details">Details</string>
    <string name="filter_all">All Parks</string>

    <!-- Categories -->
    <string name="category_popular">Popular</string>
    <string name="category_geothermal">Geothermal</string>
    <string name="category_wildlife">Wildlife</string>
    <string name="category_mountains">Mountains</string>
    <string name="category_waterfalls">Waterfalls</string>
    <string name="category_unesco">UNESCO</string>
    <string name="category_coastal">Coastal</string>
    <string name="category_hiking">Hiking</string>
    <string name="category_autumn">Autumn</string>
    <string name="category_desert">Desert</string>
    <string name="category_canyons">Canyons</string>
    <string name="category_caves">Caves</string>
    <string name="category_forests">Forests</string>
    <string name="category_volcanoes">Volcanoes</string>
    <string name="category_islands">Islands</string>
    <string name="category_historical">Historical</string>
    <string name="category_rivers">Rivers</string>
    <string name="category_glaciers">Glaciers</string>
    <string name="category_arctic">Arctic</string>
    <string name="category_dunes">Dunes</string>
    <string name="category_tropical">Tropical</string>

    <!-- Park Names -->
    <string name="park_acadia_name">Acadia</string>
    <string name="park_american_samoa_name">American Samoa</string>
    <string name="park_arches_name">Arches</string>
    <string name="park_badlands_name">Badlands</string>
    <string name="park_big_bend_name">Big Bend</string>
    <string name="park_biscayne_name">Biscayne</string>
    <string name="park_black_canyon_name">Black Canyon of the Gunnison</string>
    <string name="park_bryce_canyon_name">Bryce Canyon</string>
    <string name="park_canyonlands_name">Canyonlands</string>
    <string name="park_capitol_reef_name">Capitol Reef</string>
    <string name="park_carlsbad_caverns_name">Carlsbad Caverns</string>
    <string name="park_channel_islands_name">Channel Islands</string>
    <string name="park_congaree_name">Congaree</string>
    <string name="park_crater_lake_name">Crater Lake</string>
    <string name="park_cuyahoga_valley_name">Cuyahoga Valley</string>
    <string name="park_death_valley_name">Death Valley</string>
    <string name="park_denali_name">Denali</string>
    <string name="park_dry_tortugas_name">Dry Tortugas</string>
    <string name="park_everglades_name">Everglades</string>
    <string name="park_gates_of_the_arctic_name">Gates of the Arctic</string>
    <string name="park_gateway_arch_name">Gateway Arch</string>
    <string name="park_glacier_name">Glacier</string>
    <string name="park_glacier_bay_name">Glacier Bay</string>
    <string name="park_grand_canyon_name">Grand Canyon</string>
    <string name="park_grand_teton_name">Grand Teton</string>
    <string name="park_great_basin_name">Great Basin</string>
    <string name="park_great_sand_dunes_name">Great Sand Dunes</string>
    <string name="park_great_smoky_mountains_name">Great Smoky Mountains</string>
    <string name="park_guadalupe_mountains_name">Guadalupe Mountains</string>
    <string name="park_haleakala_name">Haleakalā</string>
    <string name="park_hawaii_volcanoes_name">Hawaiʻi Volcanoes</string>
    <string name="park_hot_springs_name">Hot Springs</string>
    <string name="park_indiana_dunes_name">Indiana Dunes</string>
    <string name="park_isle_royale_name">Isle Royale</string>
    <string name="park_joshua_tree_name">Joshua Tree</string>
    <string name="park_katmai_name">Katmai</string>
    <string name="park_kenai_fjords_name">Kenai Fjords</string>
    <string name="park_kings_canyon_name">Kings Canyon</string>
    <string name="park_kobuk_valley_name">Kobuk Valley</string>
    <string name="park_lake_clark_name">Lake Clark</string>
    <string name="park_lassen_volcanic_name">Lassen Volcanic</string>
    <string name="park_mammoth_cave_name">Mammoth Cave</string>
    <string name="park_mesa_verde_name">Mesa Verde</string>
    <string name="park_mount_rainier_name">Mount Rainier</string>
    <string name="park_new_river_gorge_name">New River Gorge</string>
    <string name="park_north_cascades_name">North Cascades</string>
    <string name="park_olympic_name">Olympic</string>
    <string name="park_petrified_forest_name">Petrified Forest</string>
    <string name="park_pinnacles_name">Pinnacles</string>
    <string name="park_redwood_name">Redwood</string>
    <string name="park_rocky_mountain_name">Rocky Mountain</string>
    <string name="park_saguaro_name">Saguaro</string>
    <string name="park_sequoia_name">Sequoia</string>
    <string name="park_shenandoah_name">Shenandoah</string>
    <string name="park_theodore_roosevelt_name">Theodore Roosevelt</string>
    <string name="park_virgin_islands_name">Virgin Islands</string>
    <string name="park_voyageurs_name">Voyageurs</string>
    <string name="park_white_sands_name">White Sands</string>
    <string name="park_wind_cave_name">Wind Cave</string>
    <string name="park_wrangell_st_elias_name">Wrangell–St. Elias</string>
    <string name="park_yellowstone_name">Yellowstone</string>
    <string name="park_yosemite_name">Yosemite</string>
    <string name="park_zion_name">Zion</string>

    <!-- Park Descriptions -->
    <string name="park_acadia_description">Experience the rugged beauty of Maine\'s coast, where granite peaks meet the Atlantic Ocean. Acadia features diverse woodlands, scenic carriage roads, and the iconic Cadillac Mountain, the first place in the U.S. to see the sunrise.</string>
    <string name="park_american_samoa_description">A remote South Pacific paradise featuring tropical rainforests, vibrant coral reefs, and dramatic volcanic peaks. It is the only U.S. National Park located south of the equator, preserving Samoan culture and pristine ecosystems.</string>
    <string name="park_arches_description">Discover a red-rock wonderland home to over 2,000 natural sandstone arches and soaring pinnacles. The park\'s unique geological formations, including the famous Delicate Arch, have been sculpted by millions of years of erosion.</string>
    <string name="park_badlands_description">A landscape of striking buttes, pinnacles, and spires mixed with the largest undisturbed mixed-grass prairie in the United States. The park\'s rugged terrain is rich in prehistoric fossils, offering a glimpse into ancient ecosystems.</string>
    <string name="park_big_bend_description">Where the Chihuahuan Desert meets the rugged Chisos Mountains and the winding Rio Grande. This vast wilderness offers dramatic canyons, star-filled night skies, and a diverse array of desert-adapted plants and animals.</string>
    <string name="park_biscayne_description">A unique aquatic sanctuary that is 95% underwater, protecting a rare combination of turquoise waters, emerald islands, and coral reefs. It serves as a vital habitat for manatees, sea turtles, and hundreds of species of tropical fish.</string>
    <string name="park_black_canyon_description">Named for its deep, narrow, and dark depths, this canyon features some of the steepest cliffs and oldest rock in North America. The Gunnison River has carved through Precambrian rock for millions of years, creating a dramatic vertical landscape.</string>
    <string name="park_bryce_canyon_description">A spectacular collection of giant natural amphitheaters filled with thousands of colorful limestone hoodoos. The park\'s high altitude and unique erosion patterns create a surreal landscape of red, orange, and white rock spires.</string>
    <string name="park_canyonlands_description">A vast wilderness of countless canyons and fantastically formed buttes carved by the Colorado River and its tributaries. The park is divided into four distinct districts, each offering a unique perspective on the power of water and gravity.</string>
    <string name="park_capitol_reef_description">A hidden treasure in Utah\'s red-rock country, protecting the Waterpocket Fold, a massive 100-mile long wrinkle in the Earth\'s crust. It features colorful cliffs, hidden arches, and the historic orchards of Fruita.</string>
    <string name="park_carlsbad_caverns_description">Explore an underground world of more than 119 caves, including the massive \'Big Room\' limestone chamber. These ancient caverns feature stunning stalactites, stalagmites, and an incredible diversity of cave formations.</string>
    <string name="park_channel_islands_description">Five unique islands scattered along the California coast, often called the \'Galápagos of North America.\' They are home to endemic species, dramatic sea caves, and some of the richest kelp forests in the world.</string>
    <string name="park_congaree_description">The largest intact expanse of old-growth bottomland hardwood forest remaining in the southeastern United States. Towering bald cypress and water tupelo trees thrive in this lush, biodiverse floodplain ecosystem.</string>
    <string name="park_crater_lake_description">The deepest lake in the United States, famous for its intense blue color and incredible clarity. It was formed inside the collapsed caldera of Mount Mazama, a volcano that erupted violently over 7,000 years ago.</string>
    <string name="park_cuyahoga_valley_description">A surprising refuge of natural beauty and rural history nestled between the urban centers of Cleveland and Akron. It preserves the scenic landscape along the Cuyahoga River and the historic Ohio &amp; Erie Canal.</string>
    <string name="park_death_valley_description">The hottest, driest, and lowest national park in the U.S., featuring a landscape of extremes. From salt flats and sand dunes to rugged mountains and colorful canyons, it is a place of stark and haunting beauty.</string>
    <string name="park_denali_description">Home to North America\'s highest peak, the majestic Denali, and over six million acres of wild subarctic land. The park\'s vast tundra and boreal forests support grizzly bears, wolves, caribou, and Dall sheep.</string>
    <string name="park_dry_tortugas_description">A remote cluster of seven islands in the Gulf of Mexico, accessible only by boat or seaplane. It features the massive 19th-century Fort Jefferson, vibrant coral reefs, and significant bird nesting colonies.</string>
    <string name="park_everglades_description">The largest tropical wilderness in the United States and a UNESCO World Heritage site. This \'River of Grass\' provides a critical habitat for rare and endangered species like the Florida panther and American crocodile.</string>
    <string name="park_gates_of_the_arctic_description">A vast wilderness located entirely north of the Arctic Circle, with no roads, trails, or visitor facilities. It preserves a wild and remote landscape of rugged mountains, winding rivers, and ancient caribou migration routes.</string>
    <string name="park_gateway_arch_description">An iconic 630-foot stainless steel monument on the banks of the Mississippi River. It symbolizes St. Louis\'s historic role as the \'Gateway to the West\' during the era of American expansion.</string>
    <string name="park_glacier_description">Known as the \'Crown of the Continent,\' this park features rugged mountains, pristine alpine meadows, and over 130 named lakes. It is home to spectacular carved glacial valleys and a diverse array of wildlife, including mountain goats.</string>
    <string name="park_glacier_bay_description">A stunning landscape of massive tidewater glaciers, ice-capped mountains, and deep, narrow fjords. The park is a living laboratory of glacial retreat and a sanctuary for humpback whales, sea otters, and harbor seals.</string>
    <string name="park_grand_canyon_description">One of the most spectacular natural wonders on Earth, carved by the Colorado River over millions of years. Its immense size and intricate landscape reveal two billion years of Earth\'s geological history.</string>
    <string name="park_grand_teton_description">A majestic landscape of jagged peaks rising abruptly from the Jackson Hole valley floor without any foothills. The park features pristine alpine lakes, diverse wildlife, and the winding Snake River.</string>
    <string name="park_great_basin_description">A remote desert landscape known for its ancient bristlecone pines, some of the oldest living organisms on Earth. It also features the marble-walled Lehman Caves and the 13,063-foot Wheeler Peak.</string>
    <string name="park_great_sand_dunes_description">Home to the tallest sand dunes in North America, nestled against the rugged backdrop of the Sangre de Cristo Mountains. This diverse landscape also includes alpine lakes, tundra, and ancient forests.</string>
    <string name="park_great_smoky_mountains_description">America\'s most visited national park, world-renowned for its diversity of plant and animal life. The park features ancient mountains shrouded in a blue-gray mist and remnants of Southern Appalachian culture.</string>
    <string name="park_guadalupe_mountains_description">This park features the world\'s premier fossil reef and the four highest peaks in Texas. Its diverse ecosystems range from desert floor to high-altitude forests of ponderosa pine and Douglas fir.</string>
    <string name="park_haleakala_description">A massive shield volcano on the island of Maui, featuring a surreal crater landscape that resembles another planet. It is home to the rare silversword plant and is a legendary spot for viewing sunrises and sunsets.</string>
    <string name="park_hawaii_volcanoes_description">Experience the power of creation and destruction at one of the most active volcanic sites on Earth. The park protects the summits of Kīlauea and Mauna Loa, where volcanic eruptions have reshaped the landscape for millennia.</string>
    <string name="park_hot_springs_description">A unique urban national park preserving historic bathhouses and natural thermal springs. For over a century, visitors have come to these waters for their supposed healing properties and relaxation.</string>
    <string name="park_indiana_dunes_description">A diverse landscape of rugged sand dunes, wetlands, prairies, and oak savannas along the southern shore of Lake Michigan. It is a haven for birdwatchers and home to an incredible variety of rare plants.</string>
    <string name="park_isle_royale_description">A remote island wilderness in Lake Superior, accessible only by boat or seaplane. It is world-renowned for its long-term predator-prey studies of wolves and moose in a closed ecosystem.</string>
    <string name="park_joshua_tree_description">Where the high Mojave Desert meets the low Colorado Desert, creating a landscape of twisted Joshua trees and massive granite boulders. It is a paradise for rock climbers, hikers, and stargazers.</string>
    <string name="park_katmai_description">A wild landscape of volcanoes and rivers, famous for the world\'s highest concentration of brown bears. Each summer, bears gather at Brooks Falls to feast on sockeye salmon migrating upstream.</string>
    <string name="park_kenai_fjords_description">A dramatic coastal landscape where the massive Harding Icefield meets the sea in a series of deep fjords. The park is a sanctuary for marine mammals, including whales, sea lions, and puffins.</string>
    <string name="park_kings_canyon_description">A landscape of deep canyons, high peaks, and giant sequoia groves adjacent to Sequoia National Park. It features some of the deepest canyons in North America and spectacular high-altitude wilderness.</string>
    <string name="park_kobuk_valley_description">A remote Arctic landscape known for the Great Kobuk Sand Dunes and the massive caribou migration. Located north of the Arctic Circle, it has no roads and preserves a wild, undisturbed ecosystem.</string>
    <string name="park_lake_clark_description">A stunning wilderness of active volcanoes, turquoise lakes, and jagged mountain peaks. Accessible only by air, it preserves a diverse landscape where the Alaska and Aleutian Ranges meet.</string>
    <string name="park_lassen_volcanic_description">A unique landscape that features all four types of volcanoes found in the world. The park is home to bubbling mud pots, steaming vents, and clear alpine lakes sculpted by volcanic activity.</string>
    <string name="park_mammoth_cave_description">The world\'s longest known cave system, with over 400 miles of explored passages. This underground labyrinth features incredible limestone formations, vast chambers, and a unique ecosystem of cave-dwelling species.</string>
    <string name="park_mesa_verde_description">A UNESCO World Heritage site that protects over 5,000 archaeological sites, including some of the best-preserved Ancestral Puebloan cliff dwellings. It offers a fascinating look at the life and culture of ancient inhabitants.</string>
    <string name="park_mount_rainier_description">An iconic, glacier-clad active volcano that dominates the Pacific Northwest horizon. It is encased in over 25 glaciers and features stunning subalpine wildflower meadows and ancient forests.</string>
    <string name="park_new_river_gorge_description">A rugged, whitewater river flowing through a deep canyon in the Appalachian Mountains. It features one of the oldest rivers on the continent and is world-famous for its rafting, climbing, and the iconic New River Gorge Bridge.</string>
    <string name="park_north_cascades_description">A vast wilderness of jagged peaks, deep valleys, and over 300 glaciers—the most in any U.S. park outside Alaska. It is a haven for mountaineers and hikers seeking a remote and challenging alpine experience.</string>
    <string name="park_olympic_description">A diverse landscape that includes glacier-capped peaks, old-growth temperate rainforests, and over 70 miles of wild Pacific coastline. It is a UNESCO World Heritage site and a sanctuary for unique species like the Roosevelt elk.</string>
    <string name="park_petrified_forest_description">A colorful landscape of the Painted Desert and large deposits of 225-million-year-old petrified wood. The park also features ancient petroglyphs and remnants of early human habitation.</string>
    <string name="park_pinnacles_description">A unique landscape of massive monoliths, spires, and talus caves formed by an ancient volcano. It is a critical nesting site for the endangered California condor and a popular destination for rock climbers.</string>
    <string name="park_redwood_description">Home to the tallest trees on Earth, some of which have lived for over 2,000 years. This coastal park protects nearly half of the world\'s remaining old-growth redwoods and a diverse array of marine and forest life.</string>
    <string name="park_rocky_mountain_description">Experience the majesty of the high Rockies, featuring over 60 peaks above 12,000 feet. The park offers spectacular alpine tundra, the Continental Divide, and a wealth of wildlife, including elk and bighorn sheep.</string>
    <string name="park_saguaro_description">Protecting the giant saguaro cactus, the universal symbol of the American West. The park features two districts on either side of Tucson, showcasing the beauty and biodiversity of the Sonoran Desert.</string>
    <string name="park_sequoia_description">A land of giants, home to the General Sherman tree—the world\'s largest living tree by volume. The park also features the massive granite dome of Moro Rock and the deep depths of the Crystal Cave.</string>
    <string name="park_shenandoah_description">A scenic escape in the Blue Ridge Mountains, featuring the famous 105-mile Skyline Drive. The park is home to lush forests, cascading waterfalls, and spectacular vistas of the Shenandoah Valley.</string>
    <string name="park_theodore_roosevelt_description">A rugged landscape of colorful badlands where the 26th President once ranched and found inspiration. It is a sanctuary for bison, wild horses, and elk, preserving the wild spirit of the American West.</string>
    <string name="park_virgin_islands_description">A Caribbean paradise of white sand beaches, turquoise waters, and vibrant coral reefs. The park also protects historic sugar plantation ruins and the diverse tropical ecosystems of St. John.</string>
    <string name="park_voyageurs_description">A unique water-based park of interconnected lakes and boreal forests along the Canadian border. It is named for the French-Canadian fur traders who once navigated these scenic waterways by canoe.</string>
    <string name="park_white_sands_description">Located in the Tularosa Basin, this park features the world\'s largest gypsum dunefield, covering 275 square miles. The brilliant white dunes create a surreal and ever-shifting landscape unlike anywhere else on Earth.</string>
    <string name="park_wind_cave_description">One of the world\'s longest and most complex caves, famous for its rare \'boxwork\' formations. Above ground, the park preserves a native prairie ecosystem where bison and pronghorn roam freely.</string>
    <string name="park_wrangell_st_elias_description">The largest national park in the United States, spanning 13.2 million acres of rugged mountains and massive glaciers. It contains 9 of the 16 highest peaks in the U.S. and a wealth of historic mining sites.</string>
    <string name="park_yellowstone_description">The world\'s first national park and a geothermal wonderland home to Old Faithful and over half of the world\'s geysers. Its vast wilderness supports a rich ecosystem of grizzly bears, wolves, and free-ranging bison.</string>
    <string name="park_yosemite_description">A world-renowned sanctuary of granite cliffs, spectacular waterfalls, and ancient giant sequoias. Iconic landmarks like El Capitan and Half Dome draw millions of visitors to the heart of the Sierra Nevada.</string>
    <string name="park_zion_description">Follow the paths of ancient people and gaze up at massive sandstone cliffs of cream, pink, and red. The park\'s dramatic canyons, including the Zion Narrows, offer some of the most spectacular hiking in the world.</string>
    <string name="progress">PROGRESS</string>
    <string name="stamps_collected">STAMPS COLLECTED</string>
    <string name="sort_recent">Recent</string>
    <string name="sort_states">States</string>
    <string name="sort_alphabetical">A-Z</string>
    <string name="interactive_map">INTERACTIVE MAP</string>
    <string name="collected">STAMP COLLECTED!</string>
    <string name="collect">I\'VE BEEN THERE!</string>
    <string name="stamp_info">Add a stamp to your digital passport</string>
    <string name="back">Back</string>
    <string name="parks_count"> / %1$d Parks</string>
    <string name="percentage_complete">%1$d%% Complete</string>
    <string name="wilderness_quote">\"The wilderness is calling and I must go.\"</string>

    <!-- Settings -->
    <string name="settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="general">GENERAL</string>
    <string name="app_language">App Language</string>
    <string name="language_english">English (United States)</string>
    <string name="language_russian">Russian</string>
    <string name="units">UNITS</string>
    <string name="distance_units">Distance Units</string>
    <string name="metric">Metric</string>
    <string name="imperial">Imperial</string>
    <string name="temperature">Temperature</string>
    <string name="celsius">Celsius</string>
    <string name="fahrenheit">Fahrenheit</string>
    <string name="AL">Alabama</string>
    <string name="AK">Alaska</string>
    <string name="AZ">Arizona</string>
    <string name="AR">Arkansas</string>
    <string name="CA">California</string>
    <string name="CO">Colorado</string>
    <string name="CT">Connecticut</string>
    <string name="DE">Delaware</string>
    <string name="FL">Florida</string>
    <string name="GA">Georgia</string>
    <string name="HI">Hawaii</string>
    <string name="ID">Idaho</string>
    <string name="IL">Illinois</string>
    <string name="IN">Indiana</string>
    <string name="IA">Iowa</string>
    <string name="KS">Kansas</string>
    <string name="KY">Kentucky</string>
    <string name="LA">Louisiana</string>
    <string name="ME">Maine</string>
    <string name="MD">Maryland</string>
    <string name="MA">Massachusetts</string>
    <string name="MI">Michigan</string>
    <string name="MN">Minnesota</string>
    <string name="MS">Mississippi</string>
    <string name="MO">Missouri</string>
    <string name="MT">Montana</string>
    <string name="NE">Nebraska</string>
    <string name="NV">Nevada</string>
    <string name="NH">New Hampshire</string>
    <string name="NJ">New Jersey</string>
    <string name="NM">New Mexico</string>
    <string name="NY">New York</string>
    <string name="NC">North Carolina</string>
    <string name="ND">North Dakota</string>
    <string name="OH">Ohio</string>
    <string name="OK">Oklahoma</string>
    <string name="OR">Oregon</string>
    <string name="PA">Pennsylvania</string>
    <string name="RI">Rhode Island</string>
    <string name="SC">South Carolina</string>
    <string name="SD">South Dakota</string>
    <string name="TN">Tennessee</string>
    <string name="TX">Texas</string>
    <string name="UT">Utah</string>
    <string name="VT">Vermont</string>
    <string name="VA">Virginia</string>
    <string name="WA">Washington</string>
    <string name="WV">West Virginia</string>
    <string name="WI">Wisconsin</string>
    <string name="WY">Wyoming</string>
    <string name="DC">District of Columbia</string>
    <string name="AS">American Samoa</string>
    <string name="VI">Virgin Islands</string>

</resources>